hannaandersson.com 2019-04-16

# Privacy Statement

Last updated: October 23, 2018

## WHAT IS THE SCOPE OF THIS POLICY?

This policy applies to Hanna Andersson, LLC's ("Hanna" or "Hanna Andersson") treatment of personal information collected through our website, mobile site or apps and when you submit personal information to Hanna via social media channels (“Sites”). This policy also applies to personal information collected through offline interactions with Hanna, such as phone calls with our customer service team and information you provide when you visit our retail stores or events. Hanna Andersson is located in the United States. We process your personal information in the United States.

This policy applies to "personal information," which means data that can be used to identify you individually.

## WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED?

Hanna collects two different types of information about you: First is what you may provide us when you interact with Hanna Andersson. Second is certain data (including personal information) that is collected automatically as you use the Sites.

### A. PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE DIRECTLY

You may provide us with certain personal information when making a purchase (online, through the call center or at a store), logging into your account, registering for an account, requesting a catalog, signing up for email updates, participating in a survey, interacting with Hanna (via social media, chat, email or phone), or participating in our referral program.

The personal information you may provide us includes:

  * Name and contact information, such as mailing address, email address, and phone number
  * Birthday (month and day only) and gender
  * Number of children you have, and their age and gender
  * Photos, reviews, emails, chat content, and other feedback you submit
  * Passwords
  * Payment data
  * For registry owners, pregnancy status and expected due date of your child

Much of this information is optional. For example, when you purchase products from the Hanna Andersson website, you must provide your name, email address, shipping/billing address, and payment card data, but you are not required to create an account. When you check out as a guest, we use your personal information to fulfill your order, and otherwise as permitted under this policy.

### B. PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY

Certain personal information is collected automatically when you use our Sites. This personal information generally falls into these categories:

  * Purchase histories: We maintain a record of your past purchases to assist you with returns and exchanges, as well as future orders.
  * Device data: For example, when you visit our website, we collect your IP address. If you access our website from a mobile device, we collect unique device IDs.
  * Location data: We collect location data, which helps us understand where our customers are located.
  * Interactions data: We maintain a record of your activity on our online Sites, including how you use our website, which products you view, and which emails you receive. We also collect information about the site you visited before navigating to our website.

Some of this information is collected via cookies, as described below. We may connect personal information collected automatically with data we already have about you, so we can identify you as a Hanna customer. For example, we may link your activity in a Hanna store to your use of the Hanna website. This allows us to provide the best shopping experience possible. We examine metrics such as how you are shopping through our Sites, the performance of our marketing efforts, and your response to those marketing efforts.

## WHAT ARE COOKIES AND HOW DOES HANNA USE THEM?

Hanna and its trusted business partners employ technology features known as cookies and tags to understand how you interact with our Sites and email messages. Read more about the cookies Hanna uses and how you can opt out by visiting our Cookie Notice at <https://www.hannaandersson.com/cookie-notice.html>.

## DO-NOT-TRACK REQUESTS

Your Internet browser and mobile device may allow you to adjust your browser settings so that "do not track" requests are sent to the websites you visit. Hanna does not respond to "do not track" requests at this time.

## HOW IS MY INFORMATION USED?

Personal information that is collected is used in the following ways:

  * To confirm and process your order and to maintain your purchase history.
  * To contact you regarding updates to your order or to remind you about items left in your online shopping cart.
  * To provide the Sites to you.
  * To share the content you submit.
  * To send you information regarding website and product updates, special promotions, new store openings, etc. Marketing information may be provided via mail or email.
  * To comply with regulatory requirements and internal policies for maintaining records.
  * To conduct internal reviews of our Sites and to help us better understand how you use our Sites.
  * To tailor our product offerings and marketing promotions and make your shopping experience more enjoyable and convenient.
  * To ensure that we've responded to your inquiries.
  * To protect the security and integrity of our Sites.
  * To comply with court orders and legal process, and to enforce our Terms of Use and this Statement.
  * For any other legal business or marketing purposes that are not inconsistent with the terms of this policy.

## HOW WILL MY INFORMATION BE SHARED?

### A. SERVICE PROVIDERS

Hanna does not sell, rent or trade our customer email addresses with third parties for their own marketing purposes. However, we may share your personal information with our third-party distributors, vendors, suppliers and other service providers who provide services to us or on our behalf, such as operating and supporting the Sites, performing analytics, marketing or consulting services, assisting us with the preparation and mailing of our business and marketing communications, and with order processing and fulfillment functions.

When you order a product, Hanna provides your name and mailing address (not your email address) to other reputable partner companies who may send you mailings. If you do not wish for us to share this information with these companies, you can add your name to our "Opt Out" list by sending us an email at [customerservice@hannaAndersson.com](mailto:customerservice@hannaAndersson.com) or calling 800-222-0544. If you send an email, please be sure to provide your name and mailing address in the message and include “Opt-out of Mailings” in the subject line.

### B. OTHER USERS

Where you choose to participate in certain activities through the Sites, your personal information may be posted publicly. These activities are optional. For example:

  * If you submit a product review, the information you provide may be posted on the product page or other locations in accordance with our Terms of Use.
  * When you use the hashtag #HANNAJAMS, #ILOVEMYHANNAS, or other Hanna-related hashtags on Instagram, your photo automatically becomes part of the public gallery on our Site.
  * When you create a baby registry, your pregnancy status, due date, and other information you provide in connection with the registry will be set to "private" by default (available only to those with a link). You can choose whether to make your registry private or public.

### C. TARGETED ADVERTISING

We contract with third-party service providers to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and sometimes on our Site. These third parties may use cookies to collect information about your Site visits, as described in our Cookie Notice. They may also use information about your visits to this and other websites to target advertisements that are more relevant to you. These targeted advertisements may appear on our Site or on other sites that you visit. The information is collected through the use of a pixel tag, which is industry standard technology used by most major web sites. Other than IP addresses, no personally identifiable information is collected in this process.

### D. ANALYTICS

Hanna uses Google Analytics to study how users interact with our Sites. To learn more about Google's privacy practices, visit Google's Privacy & Terms at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>. Hanna may engage other analytics providers from time to time. These third parties may combine your information with the information of other consumers for analytics purposes. Some analytics providers use cookies, and you may opt out of those cookies by visiting <https://www.hannaandersson.com/cookie-notice.html> to manage your cookie preferences.

### E. TRANSFER OR ASSIGNMENT IN CONNECTION WITH BUSINESS TRANSFERS OR BANKRUPTCY

In the event of a merger, acquisition, reorganization, bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of our assets, any user information owned or controlled by us may be among the assets transferred to third parties. As part of this type of transaction, we reserve the right to transfer or assign your personal information to third parties. Other than to the extent ordered by a bankruptcy or other court, or as otherwise agreed to by you, the use and disclosure of all transferred user information will be subject to this policy. However, any information you submit or that is collected after this type of transfer may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by the successor entity.

### F. RESPONSE TO SUBPOENAS OR COURT ORDERS OR TO PROTECT OUR RIGHTS

We may disclose your information to government authorities or other third parties if:

  * you have given us permission to share your information;
  * we are required to do so by law, or in response to a subpoena or court order;
  * we believe in our sole discretion that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect against fraud, or to protect our property or other rights or those of other users of the Sites, third parties or the public at large; or
  * we believe that you have abused a Service by using it to attack or gain unauthorized access to a system or to engage in spamming or other conduct that violates applicable laws or Hanna's website terms of use.

### G. TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Your personal information may be collected, stored or processed by Hanna Andersson or other third parties (as described above) in countries other than the country in which your personal information originally was shared, including in the United States. The laws in those countries may not provide the same level of data protection as the country in which you initially provided your personal information. Hanna Andersson will enter into appropriate agreements when sharing your personal information with third parties to enable the lawful processing of your information.

### H. AGGREGATE INFORMATION

We may share aggregated or de-identified information without restriction. While this information will not identify you personally, in some instances third parties may be able to combine this aggregate information with other data they have about you, or that they receive from third parties, in a manner that allows them to identify you personally.

## HOW DO I REVIEW OR UPDATE MY INFORMATION?

If you are a registered user, you may access your information by signing in and clicking on "My Account" at the top of the page. You may make changes to your personal information, email preferences, and mailing preferences on this page. Be sure to click the "Save" button to save your changes. 

You can also contact customer service to access or make changes to your information by calling 800-222-0544 or sending an email to [customercarecenter@hannaAndersson.com](mailto:customercarecenter@hannaAndersson.com).

## HOW DO I OPT OUT?

If you wish to opt out of allowing certain cookies, please visit our Cookie Notice at <https://www.hannaandersson.com/cookie-notice.html> to manage your cookie preferences. Please note that the way the cookie management tool functions is by actually dropping a cookie on your browser. This delivers the message: “stop allowing cookies.” Therefore, if you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies, or use a different computer or Internet browser, you’ll need to renew your cookie management choices.

You may opt out of advertising provided directly by Hanna: If you do not wish to receive marketing correspondence (including catalogs and emails), please email us at [customercarecenter@hannaAndersson.com](mailto:customercarecenter@hannaAndersson.com) or call us at 800-222-0544. If you only wish to unsubscribe from emails, you can click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email you received or change your email preferences in your account. If you send an email to customer service, please be sure to include “Opt-Out” in the subject line and include your name, address, and/or email address as it appears on the email or mailing you received from Hanna and indicate which list(s) you would like to be removed from (email and/or mailing). 

We maintain a "Do Not Mail" file to ensure we honor your "opt out" requests for print mailings. Please note that, since mailings are arranged in advance, it may take up to eight weeks for your print mailing "opt out" to become effective. If you make purchases from our website, you will still receive order and shipping confirmation emails. In addition, customer service may contact you by phone, email, or mail with questions related to your order.

You may also delete your Hanna Andersson account by logging into your account and clicking on the “Delete my account” link. If you delete your account, your account will be deactivated, you will be opted out of future email communications, you will no longer receive catalogues, and your personal information will be deleted from Hanna systems other than as may be retained by Hanna under applicable law. Note that it may take up to 30 days for this request to be complete.

## FOR USERS BASED IN THE EUROPEAN UNION

The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation and other data protection laws grant you certain rights in relation to your personal information. Where applicable to you, you can:

  * request access to your personal information and how we process it
  * request correction of the personal information that we hold about you
  * ask us to delete your personal information
  * object to our processing your personal information
  * ask us to restrict the processing of your personal information
  * request the transfer of your personal information to you or to a third party
  * withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal information. 

Withdrawing your consent to our processing of your personal information will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. You should also be aware that if you do withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain services to you. Where this is the case, we will let you know at the time you withdraw your consent. Please note that even after you have withdrawn your consent, we may continue to process your personal information to the extent required or otherwise permitted by law, in particular, in connection with exercising and defending our legal rights or meeting our legal and regulatory obligations.

In some cases, as we have previously noted within this Privacy Statement, you are able to access, correct and update your personal information directly by logging into your account. If you are an EU resident and would like to make a data subject request, please:

  * Send us an email at individualrights@hannaandersson.com; or
  * Contact us via the individual rights manager, available at: [](https://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/validation?rid=47097926-ad35-4604-ab44-3a17328cf1f0)

## HOW DOES HANNA PROTECT MY INFORMATION?

The security of your personal information is very important to Hanna, and we have implemented measures to ensure your information is processed confidentially, accurately, and securely. Our website is PCI DSS compliant and uses SSL/TLS (Secure Sockets Layer) technology to encrypt your order information, such as your name, address, and credit card number, during data transmission. We use a third-party payment processor, which is also PCI DSS compliant.

The Hanna website also displays the Norton Secured seal, which indicates that the site has been authenticated by DigiCert,Inc. and that confidential transactions with our site are secured by SSL/TLS encryption. 

Our customer service center and stores also operate over a private, secure network.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## HOW DOES HANNA PROTECT CHILDREN'S PRIVACY?

We at Hanna Andersson are concerned about the safety and security of children. All children's products we sell are for purchase by adults only. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 16 without prior verifiable parental consent. If we become aware that an individual is under the age of 16 has provided personal information to Hanna Andersson, for any purpose without prior verifiable parental consent, we will delete his or her information from our files.

## WHAT IF THERE ARE CHANGES MADE TO THIS POLICY?

As Hanna Andersson offers new products and services, this Privacy Statement is expected to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the Privacy Statement at any time, for any reason, without notice to you, other than the posting of the amended Privacy Statement at this Site. We encourage customers to periodically review this policy to stay informed about how we collect, use, and protect customer information. You can see when this Privacy Statement was last updated by checking the “last updated” date displayed at the beginning of this Privacy Statement.

## HOW DOES THIS POLICY APPLY TO SITES LINKED WITH THE HANNA WEBSITE?

Please note that this Privacy Statement applies only to our Sites and not to any third-party websites, even where our Sites may contain links to those other websites. We strongly recommend you review the privacy policies of any third-party sites you visit to understand the data collection and use practices of that third party.
